<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><rss version="2.0"
	xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"
	xmlns:wfw="http://wellformedweb.org/CommentAPI/"
	xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"
	xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"
	xmlns:sy="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/syndication/"
	xmlns:slash="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/slash/"
	>

<channel>
	<title>trivia &#8211; Veritenze</title>
	<atom:link href="https://veritenze.com/tag/trivia/feed/" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
	<link>https://veritenze.com</link>
	<description></description>
	<lastBuildDate>Mon, 03 Dec 2018 16:24:35 +0000</lastBuildDate>
	<language>en-US</language>
	<sy:updatePeriod>hourly</sy:updatePeriod>
	<sy:updateFrequency>1</sy:updateFrequency>
	<generator>https://wordpress.org/?v=4.9.8</generator>

<image>
	<url>https://veritenze.com/wp-content/uploads/2018/10/cropped-icon-32x32.png</url>
	<title>trivia &#8211; Veritenze</title>
	<link>https://veritenze.com</link>
	<width>32</width>
	<height>32</height>
</image> 
	<item>
		<title>Trivia with Veritenze: The World of Amantia (Part 2)</title>
		<link>https://veritenze.com/2018/12/03/trivia-with-veritenze-the-world-of-amantia-part-2/</link>
		<pubDate>Mon, 03 Dec 2018 16:17:48 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Veritenze]]></dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Seed of Amaranth]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Trivia]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[amantia]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[no spoilers]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[seed of amaranth]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[trivia]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[world]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://veritenze.com/?p=264</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[In our second round of trivia, we&#8217;re going to focus on the world of &#8220;Seed of Amaranth!&#8221; From its beasts to its continents, we&#8217;ll be sharing facts and background details on everything that makes up this setting. &#160; As always, it is recommended to fully play through &#8220;Seed of Amaranth&#8221;<a class="moretag" href="https://veritenze.com/2018/12/03/trivia-with-veritenze-the-world-of-amantia-part-2/"> Read more&#8230;</a>]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>In our second round of trivia, we&#8217;re going to focus on the world of &#8220;Seed of Amaranth!&#8221; From its beasts to its continents, we&#8217;ll be sharing facts and background details on everything that makes up this setting.</p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<p>As always, it is recommended to fully play through &#8220;Seed of Amaranth&#8221; before reading this trivia, as Seed is meant to be played with no prior knowledge. While this post won&#8217;t contain any direct spoilers, there&#8217;s no telling how your experience may change!</p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<p><strong>1 | The Four</strong> <strong>Continents</strong></p>
<p>While &#8220;Seed of Amaranth&#8221; takes place in the Kingdom and continent of Amantia, there are three other landmasses that make up its world. Amantia is the largest, and hypothesized to be the most irradiated. It shares a border with Nadria to the east, which has led to rising tensions. Things may be calm, but war is on the horizon. Tenunum lies beyond it, doing its best to stay out of the pending conflict. This isolationist policy is maintained with help from natural water spouts that deter invasions. Meanwhile, the distant continent of Fontania waits to the south. Little is known about this strange land.</p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<p><strong>2 | The Automata</strong></p>
<p>These mechanized creatures roam the Frontier, carrying out their ancient orders. They are relics from before the apocalypse, created for an unknown purpose. After centuries of wear and tear, most are corroded and broken down, but the more robust ones are still extremely dangerous. They are usually territorial, sticking to a certain region or ruin. Some of the most dangerous tend to be made of a strange black metal, the exact nature of which remains unknown.</p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<p><strong>3 | The Ancients</strong></p>
<p>&#8220;Ancients&#8221; denote creatures so powerful and old that they predate the apocalypse. These species have survived cataclysms in the past without changing or mutating.</p>
<p>The most famous among these are the Anubis, a race of giant jackal-men who are often the object of cult worship due to their wisdom and might. They are said to be tied to the land, allowing them to manipulate the elements around them.</p>
<p>While rare to the point of being considered mythical, the Fjallnera are very much real. While they can usually blend into human society, these colorful humanoids have one telling trait: they reincarnate upon death, keeping all of their previous knowledge and experience. Their society is based around ideas of bravery and skill, with thieves and conquerors being idolized above all others. A legendary pirate is expected to forfeit all of their earnings on death, challenging them on reincarnating to rise to even greater heights.</p>
<p>Finally, the Titanopanda are a well known but isolated race. Taking a form similar to giant pandas, but many times the size, they stay far away from human society. They are extremely intelligent and wise, something that can be seen in the giant, complicated structures they live in. A single complex can often hold over fifty of these creatures, using nothing more than bamboo and a strange fire-resistant material.</p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<p><strong>4 | The Beasts</strong></p>
<p>While the Ancients got through the apocalypse intact, beasts have been warped and twisted by it. Many new species have evolved to survive in the Frontier, adapting to negate or even harness the radiation around them.</p>
<p>Sephies were first introduced to the Frontier by mankind. Their ability to adapt was put to use, resulting in the birth of several different breeds. These horse-sized birds are often used for cargo and transport.</p>
<p>The detra are plated animals that resemble dinosaurs. These animals are speculated to have once resembled rhinoceros, but have since grown massive suits of plate armor that hide away their bodies. While herbivorous, their aggression has prevented attempts to domesticate them.</p>
<p>Nova wolves are just one of the radiation-fueled predators that call the Frontier their home. While naturally suited to live off of light and heat, the prevalence of radiation has led some of these creatures to grow to monstrous sizes, with the largest standing taller than a fully grown man. While they don&#8217;t need to eat to survive, they have come to rely on the concentration of radiation in sephies and feroraptors as a quick source of energy.</p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<p><strong>5 | Flying Squid</strong></p>
<p>The flying squid is one of Amantia&#8217;s most strange and dangerous creatures. These enormous specter-like creatures live in the upper atmosphere, where they survive using photosynthesis. While normally passive, they are uniquely dangerous when provoked. From head to tip of tentacle, these creatures tend to be over a kilometer in length.</p>
<p>The flying squid has the honor of being on of the few creatures the bounty hunter Merodach truly fears. As a teenager, he once took a bounty to kill a rogue adolescent that had wandered too close to the capital. The fight nearly killed him.</p>
<p>Mero is also afraid of ghosts.</p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<p><strong>6 | Desert Hare Recipe</strong></p>
<p>Malia is an adept cook. Due to her upbringing, she has learned how to maximize flavor and nutrition using cheap and ready ingredients. After spending time in the Frontier, she has developed a recipe on how to best prepare the rabbits found there.</p>
<ul style="font-weight: 400;">
<li>1 desert hare</li>
<li>1 diced potato</li>
<li>At least 4 carrots</li>
<li>1 large snapweed</li>
<li>2 de-radiated onions</li>
<li>5 bic eggshells</li>
<li>Water to cover</li>
</ul>
<p>After browning the hare over a campfire, throw it all in a pot and boil until ready!</p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<p><strong>7 | The Draconids</strong></p>
<p>While true dragons existed before the apocalypse, this disaster allowed many variations and breeds to rise to prominence.</p>
<p>A true dragon is a massive threat, able to dwarf most buildings. They are accordingly very rare, and wise enough to avoid large human settlements. While they lack the means to speak, it has been noted on numerous occasions that they are perfectly capable of understanding spoken language. Only one man has ever ridden a true dragon, and he was famously partners with his dragon, not its master.</p>
<p>Drakes take the opposite role: these small draconids are plentiful and small. While temperamental, they are commonly tamed for military use. The standing army of Amantia employs a large drake cavalry best known for their speed.</p>
<p>While rare, Chimaera are a noted threat. These draconids live within storm systems, feeding off of the lightning found there. While considered to be draconids, they are actually mammals resembling panthers. With the body of a panther and the mane of a great lion, they earn the title &#8220;draconid&#8221; from their massive scaled limbs and wings. While smaller than true dragons, their relative lack of intelligence brings them into conflict with humans far more often.</p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<p><strong>8 | Insects and Flora</strong></p>
<p>In the Frontier, knowing the difference between bugs and plants is a matter of life and death. Mimicry is a highly effective tactic, allowing swarms of featherwings to disguise themselves as a field of grass, waiting until their prey is truly surrounded. Then, each blade of grass will rise up, straightening its exoskeleton to form a small blade.  Mimicry is also employed by the rokks, large crabs that use stones as shelter. As they grow, they seek out larger rocks to hollow out, while the existing rock becomes soft and sensitive as it is slowly lined with neurons. A variant of featherwings, the rosenrosera can often prove to be a deadlier threat. They form small groups, resembling a flower patch, and emit noxious gases to deter predators. But if anything finds itself in the middle of the patch, the dosage will prove deadly.</p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<p><strong>9 | Viscotto</strong><br />
The viscotto tree is an extremely fickle and rare variant of apple trees. Their apples are praised above all others, especially when used for wine. They only grow fruit every ten years, restricting their availability to the richest of the rich. It is rumored that these spirits are the favorite of the current queen, Amithra.</p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<p><strong>10 | Sephies</strong></p>
<p>Sephies are giant birds that are used for transportation of people and goods, as well are warfare. These were originally created in the old world, through genetic manipulation performed on something called a &#8220;hummingbird.&#8221; Like their ancestors, sephies fly by rapidly moving their wings. Unlike hummingbirds, they have seven wings and eat meat. Sephies also have the unique ability to absorb radiation from their surroundings, which was been put to use trying to clean up the Frontier.</p>
<p>While most sephies are of the common breed, there are several varieties that are suited to different tasks. Mugens are massive, stocky creatures with an unrivaled ability to process radiation. They are usually used by the military, equipping them with metal masks to control the massive blasts of radiation they can release from their mouths. Racing sephies are lightweight, but no less powerful than their common cousins. These sephies are rare and coveted by the rich, both for their value in gambling races, and for their brilliant rainbow plumage.</p>
<p>The bounty hunter Merodach has one such racing sephie, a female named Remi. A reward for a bounty well done, she has grown to be one of the better racers in Amantia, more than earning her keep. Mero cares about her more than anything, and he wears a pendant of her feathers to remember her by when he is away.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Trivia with Veritenze: Seed of Amaranth (Part 1)</title>
		<link>https://veritenze.com/2018/10/29/trivia-with-veritenze-seed-of-amaranth-part-1/</link>
		<pubDate>Mon, 29 Oct 2018 19:55:34 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Veritenze]]></dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Seed of Amaranth]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Spoilers]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Trivia]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[amaranth]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[seed of amaranth]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[spoilers]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[trivia]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[veritenze]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://veritenze.com/?p=115</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[In this segment, we&#8217;re going to periodically post interesting facts and stories about our games. If you have any requests for topics, be sure to send them our way! With that said, let&#8217;s get on with our first round of trivia. &#160; Please be aware that these posts will contain<a class="moretag" href="https://veritenze.com/2018/10/29/trivia-with-veritenze-seed-of-amaranth-part-1/"> Read more&#8230;</a>]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>In this segment, we&#8217;re going to periodically post interesting facts and stories about our games. If you have any requests for topics, be sure to send them our way! With that said, let&#8217;s get on with our first round of trivia.</p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<p>Please be aware that these posts will contain spoilers for &#8220;Seed of Amaranth.&#8221; Amaranth is intended to be played first, with no prior knowledge needed. While we will avoid giving away major plot points, simply mentioning information about some characters can alter a player&#8217;s first experience. It is <em>highly</em> recommended that you experience the full game before reading these posts.</p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<p><strong>1 | Vale&#8217;s Original Power</strong></p>
<p>Originally, Vale&#8217;s artifact was going to give her the ability to move in parallel to the world. She would step into another version of the world, one without people, allowing her to get around without interruptions. As the story progressed, she would discover more &#8220;creative&#8221; ways to use it, such as reappearing with her fist piercing someone&#8217;s heart. This was ultimately given up in favor of a more sinister and creepy ability, the one seen in the final game.</p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<p><strong>2 | Original Names</strong></p>
<p>Of the main protagonists, only Vale has maintained her original name (although the full version was Shadow Vale)! &#8220;Seed of Amaranth&#8221; is the end result of over 10 years of storytelling between us, which has led to many changes in the cast over time. Malia&#8217;s original name was just &#8220;Heartbreak,&#8221; Amithra was Angelina, and Mero and Bel had very different names that will be revealed when we write a detailed post on the original T/S story!</p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<p><strong>3 | Home Design</strong></p>
<p>The design for Malia and Vale&#8217;s house was largely improvised by our character artist Peter. He drew inspiration from traditional Indian architecture and shanty towns. The room features jali walls, slits in the wall that allow light to enter and heat to exit. The home also contains a roof channel, a hole that allows rainwater to enter in a controlled manner, providing access to even the poorest of citizens.</p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<p><strong>4 | Technological Disparity</strong></p>
<p>It&#8217;s no secret that Amantia is home to enormous economic disparity. However, some of the key details are only show in our backgrounds! As shown in our slum ruins and houses, fire is a major source of heat and light for the kingdom&#8217;s poor. Meanwhile, our high-end interiors contain light bulbs and neon panels! As a post-apocalyptic civilization, Amantia has access to advanced technologies, some even beyond what we have in the real world. However, these technologies are rare and education is scarce, so they are only seen in wealthy areas.</p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<p><strong>5 | The Old World</strong></p>
<p>Amaranth takes place in a world that was always different from our own. Monsters like dragons and chimaera exist, as well as our own original creations such as the nova wolves. Some of these got through the apocalypse intact, while others mutated into strange new forms. While not much is known about the civilization that pre-dates Amantia, there is no denying that it was a technological paradise, relying on sciences we can scarcely imagine. We designed this world to be a unique and interesting mesh between fantasy and sci-fi, allowing us to carry these elements through to the story of &#8220;Seed of Amaranth.&#8221;</p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<p><strong>6 | Pets</strong></p>
<p>Dogs and cats were preserved alongside humanity, and resurfaced with them to resume their place in people&#8217;s homes. While they are rare in all parts of the kingdom, it is common for the elites of the Inner Ring to show them off as status symbols. Contrarily, feral dogs and stray cats can sometimes be spotted in the Outer Ring. Mero once bonded with a particularly friendly cat he called Zenny.</p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<p><strong>7 | Triscellion Colors</strong></p>
<p>The triscellion is a common icon seen throughout Amantia (most prominently in Amithra&#8217;s bedroom and a certain underground chamber). This is the symbol of the Veritenze family, as chosen by its founder. Its colors are royal purple, turquoise, and a dull red. While purple was chosen for the royal family and turquoise for the kingdom, the red was something just for them, the founder and her love.</p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<p><strong>8 | Ancient Origins</strong></p>
<p>Many names and architectural details come from ancient cultures, such as Babylonia and Sumerian. This was done to invoke a feeling of ancientness, representing the presence of the world before the apocalypse, and also the feeling of birth, of a new civilization coming into existence. Merodach is one alternate name of the Mesopotamian god Marduk. Ironically, the fact that the full name is Bel-Merodach is a complete coincidence!</p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<p><strong>9 | Nap Time</strong></p>
<p>Anyone who&#8217;s read through &#8220;Seed of Amaranth&#8221; will know that Mero has a habit of taking naps in odd places. This is due to the combined impact of both his childhood, and his current power. As a child growing up on the streets, he and Bel rarely had a consistent place to sleep. They had to learn to sleep when and where they could, with one standing guard. As Mero aged, his powers grew and he came to trust in his own strength. Now, he would laugh at the idea of needing a guard, as he (rightfully) believes no one could harm him.</p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<p><strong>10 | Veritenze</strong></p>
<p>Development is not strictly linear, and that can lead to some misconceptions. Veritenze, the royal family of Amantia, is not named after our company! In fact, the company is not named after the royal family either. Instead, Veritenze is something special, an idea that will only be understood over time.</p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
]]></content:encoded>
			</item>
	</channel>
</rss>
